

JAVIER EMMANUEL MERCEDES

Backend Developer

manuelmercedez10@gmail.com

https://github.com/KiritoXD01

linkedin.com/in/javier-emmanuel-mercedes

ABOUT ME

I'm a Backend Developer with more than 5 years of experience contributing my knowledge to multiple solutions using the Laravel ecosystem, this includes Laravel Forge for server deployments, Laravel Cashier for payment processing with Stripe, Livewire to create reactive dashboards with Filament and Inertia to create Full Stack apps using Vue JS and React JS. Also, I created applications using Nest JS, Socket IO and Redis for Realtime updates and Game backends. Currently I'm interested in the Full Laravel ecosystem to use the tools provided to deliver high efficiency systems for reporting and analytics.

EXPERIENCE

ChicksGold

Backend Engineer Contractor | May 2024 - Present

As a Backend Engineer my main task includes migrating old PHP 5 sites to Aurelia and connect them to an internal API, refactoring and making sure that all the code is secure and stable along the process.

Technologies I used:

- PHP
- Aurelia
- C#

Elaniin

Backend Developer | June 2021 - Present

As a Backend Developer I developed many projects using Filament PHP for fast admin panel creation using Laravel Livewire, also I developed the initial backend infrastructure for an NFT game Called Knight of the ether using Nest JS and Socket IO for multi-client communication, here I also created projects using Firebase as a complete backend infrastructure including Storage, Cloud Functions,

Authentication, Messaging and Cloud Firestore. Almost all the projects I worked on were deployed using Laravel Forge in AWS or Digital Ocean, for specific scenarios I used CapRover as a Container Deployment Platform to automate server configuration and service deployments using Docker.

Technologies I used:

- PHP
- Laravel
- Typescript
- Nest JS
- Vue JS
- Tailwind CSS
- React JS
- Socket IO
- Digital Ocean (Droplets, Block Storage, App Platform)
- AWS (S3, EC2, LightSail, RDS)
- CapRover
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Redis
- Firebase
- Docker
- NGINX

GRUPO VOPM

PHP Developer | August 2020 - Jun 2021

As a PHP Developer at Grupo VOPM, my role focuses on creating web applications using PHP, MySQL, and jQuery. Also, I used ETL Software to query and transform Data from various sources into data that was used for credit analytics, for these tasks I used Pentaho Data Integration and Visual Studio Integration Services.

Technologies I used:

- PHP
- jQuery
- Pentaho Data Integration
- AWS (RDS, EC2, S3)
- Apache

Prixet Technology

Senior Lead Software Engineer | October 2019 – Jun 2020 Software Developer | January 2019 – October 2019

Here I maintained and expanded a Hotspot Management system that connect to the WIFI connections available in the main specialized access points (Aruba, Ruckus, Fortinet, TP link), they have a mode that allows them to connect to a special service called RAIDUS that controls all the devices connected in the network (Time Quota, Data bandwidth, etc.) and show a custom landing page that access to information before the device connects to the internet (Google Login, Facebook login, custom form), this data was used to create heat maps, marketing analytics and user segmentation in a customer admin panel. Also, we worked sponsoring MercadExpo 2019 at UNIBE by providing the student with a custom page to buy the tickets and generate QR codes to access and track their progress in the event.

Technologies I used:

- PHP
- Laravel
- RADIUS
- MySQL
- Redis
- Bootstrap 3
- Laravel Inertia
- AWS (RDS, LightSail, EC2, S3)

EDUCATION

I graduated in Software Engineering from UNAPEC in October 2023. During that time, I acquired the following certifications:

- Certified Laravel Developer
- Nest JS Fundamentals
- MongoDB PHP Developer Path